## DAN SANDIFORD

PHD. CANDIDATE

**Profile** 

I work with numerical models of the earth, including thermal convection in the mantle, plate motion and wave propagation.

Skills

Physical forward and inverse modelling

I use a range of community-driven software to model physical phenomena such as waves, fluids and heat flow. Data science

Skills in data wrangling, time series analysis and spatial statistics / mapping.

Field work

Experience conducting managing long-term field work projects.

Written communication

Find my articles at https://www.authorea.com/users/8456

Education

Bachelor of Arts/Science, Monash University

Geology/History/Mathematics

Bachelor of Science, (Honours), University of Melbourne

Seismology

PhD, (Honours), University of Melbourne

Geophysics - Geodynamics

Geophysics Geodynamics

2014-

2005-2010

2012-2013

**Technical** 

Python

R

Linux

Experience

IBM Reasearch (Mlebourne)

Intern - Natural Resource Managment

Geological / geophysical support to IBM Research team

2014-2015

Australian Geophysical Observing System

Field/Laboratory Assistant

2012-2013

 $Se is mometer installation, maintenance.\ Petrophysical\ core\ logging,\ thermal\ properties\ testing,\ experimental\ design,\ equipment\ maintenance,\ reports.$ 

Melbourne Energy Institute

Research Assistant

2010-2012

Promoting energy research, production of web and print publications, organisation of public seminar series.

Dan Sandiford — sandd@unimelb.edu.au